All the power on earth can't change destiny.
The Godfather Part III is a crime, drama, thriller
film directed by Francis Ford Coppola.
In the midst of trying to legitimize his business dealings in 1979 New York and Italy, aging mafia don,
Michael Corleone seeks forgiveness for his sins while taking a young protege under his wing.
Michael Corleone, played by Al Pacino.
Kay Adams, played by Diane Keaton.
Connie Corleone Rizzi, played by Talia Shire.
Vincent Mancini, played by Andy Garcia.
Don Altobello, played by Eli Wallach.
Joey Zasa, played by Joe Mantegna.
The Godfather Part III is a 1990 American epic gangster film produced and directed by
Francis Ford Coppola from the screenplay co-written with Mario Puzo.
The film stars Al Pacino, Diane Keaton, Talia Shire, Andy García, Eli Wallach,
Joe Mantegna, Bridget Fonda, George Hamilton and Sofia Coppola.
It is the sequel to The Godfather (1972) and The Godfather Part II
(1974), and the final installment in The Godfather trilogy.
The film concludes the fictional story of Michael Corleone, the patriarch of the
Corleone family, who attempts to legitimize his criminal empire.
It also includes fictionalized accounts of two real-life events: the 1978 death of Pope John Paul I and
the Papal banking scandal of 1981–1982, both linked to Michael Corleone's business affairs.
Although Coppola initially refused to return for a third film, he
eventually signed to direct and write Part III.
In his audio commentary for Part II, Coppola stated that only a dire financial situation, caused by the failure of his 1982 musical
fantasy One from the Heart, compelled him to take up Paramount's long-standing offer to make a third installment.
Coppola and Puzo wanted the title to be The Death of Michael Corleone, for they felt that the first two films had told the complete
Corleone saga, so Part III would serve as the epilogue, but Paramount Pictures thought that that title was unacceptable.
Winona Ryder was initially cast in the role of Michael Corleone's daughter Mary, but
eventually left production due to other commitments and nervous exhaustion.
The role was ultimately given to Coppola's daughter Sofia, a decision
that garnered much criticism and accusations of nepotism.
Principal photography took place from late 1989 to early 1990, with
filming locations in both Italy and the United States.
The Godfather Part III premiered in Beverly Hills on December 20, 1990, and
was widely released in the United States on December 25.
The film received generally positive reviews, although it was considered inferior to
the previous films and a disappointing conclusion to the trilogy.
Critics praised Pacino’s and Garcia’s performances, as well as Coppola’s direction, cinematography,
editing, and production design, but criticized the plot and Sofia Coppola’s performance.
It grossed $136.8 million worldwide, and garnered seven nominations at the 63rd Academy
Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Supporting Actor (Garcia).
It also received seven nominations at the 48th Golden Globe Awards, including Best
Motion Picture – Drama and Best Actor – Motion Picture Drama (Pacino).
In December 2020, a recut version of the film, titled The Godfather Coda: The Death of Michael
Corleone, was released to coincide with the 30th anniversary of the original version.
Coppola called this version closer to his original vision for the
film, and it received warmer reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of daughter, new york city,
helicopter, assassination, italian american.
The tone is emotional and intense.